### Nishanth A V

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

software engineer with 1 years of startups experience in AWS, Jenkins, Docker, CI/CD, ReactJS, NodeJS, Linux(Amazon & Ubuntu), SQL, RDS, Git, Python, Bash, PostgressSQL, Java(OOPS), good written and communication skills,self-learner looking for a challenging career opportunity to resolve complex issues and collaboration in applications development.

nishanth6273@gmail.com

Bangalore, India

github.com/NishanthAV

9448734293

in linkedin.com/in/nishanth-av-a74139147

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Engineer** Diagnokare

04/2023 - 06/2023 Medical imaging and Diagnostics Achievements/Tasks

 Setup Aws Cloud infra design using cloudformation template. implementing shell scripts to setup ssl using cloudfront. solve issues related cloud server. Grafana to check status analysis of logging statements information

## Application Devloper Innovatily Pvt Ltd

10/2021 - 08/2022 Service Based SaaS Company

Bengaluru

Bengaluru

Achievements/Tasks

- Scalekrut Project- Devops role for CI/CD PIPELINE IN JENKINS using Git source code, AWS Cloud services -RDS,S3,EC2,ECR,VPC(security),Route53,EKS,AMI,Deploym ent of IP of front-end,back-end(graphql microservices architecture Containerization as a docker images for better performance of product for given problem.
- EY TALENTMINOR PROJECT-debugging Bugs using ROBOT FRAMEWORK(XPATH,ID,CLASS,DIV),Smoke Testing,Manual Testing ,unit test plans,Regression Testing,test automation,openpyxl(REFLECTING TEST CASES IN EXCEL SHEET WITH ROBOT FRAMEWORK AUTOMATION SCRIPT)after code review ,RUNNING MAVEN JAVA Spring Boot REST api MICROSERVICE JAR FILE AS SERVICE,agile tool Jira to work on sprints.

#### Cloud Intern

Verzeo Pvt Ltd

11/2020 - 12/2020 Bengaluru

Verzeo is India's Largest E-Learning Platform .

Achievements/Tasks

- CREATING VIRTUAL MACHINES/Network, INTERCONNECTING MACHINES AND NETWORK.
- BLOB STORAGE FOR STORING OBJECTS, HOST WEB APP THROUGH CLOUD MAINTAINING RESOURCE GROUP of automation solutions development products.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BE (COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING)**

Don Bosco Institute Of Technology

08/2016 - 08/2021 Bengaluru

Courses

JAVA AND J2EE

 Face authentication security using vision

#### **SKILLS**



#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

React Todo App using aws amplify (11/2022 - Present)

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

AWS LEARNING ARCHITECT (03/2023 - Present)

IBM CERTIFIED KUBERNATES AND CONTAINERS (02/2023 - Present)

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2021 (12/2021 - 12/2023)

#### **LANGUAGES**

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Kannada

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Tamil

Limited Working Proficiency

Telugu

Limited Working Proficiency

#### **INTERESTS**

